Contact

(310) 658-2303 (Mobile) azmiamir@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amir-azmi-96079a1b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Team Leadership
Project Planning
Customer Satisfaction

Languages

French English

Arabic

Certifications
CompTIA A+

Amir Azmi

Information Technology Specialist at PCW Tech Group Torrance

Summary

I have more than 10 years of experience in small and big office Windows and Apple desktop support, printer support and networking.

Logical reasoning, creative problem-solving skills, and efficient time management. with the capacity to work independently as well as in a team-driven environment.

Experience

PCW Tech Group Information Technology Specialist July 2017 - March 2019 (1 year 9 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

- Responsible for managing, coaching, and driving the performance of the Customer Service team to achieve KPIs.
- Been a point of escalation for all customer service issues.
- Ensured consistently high levels of customer excellence at all times.
- Managed to help desk support and resolve problems to ensure end-user satisfaction.
- Provided superior customer service, customer satisfaction.
- Walk end-users through a variety of problem-solving processes.
- Provided necessary training to computer users.
- · Assessed hardware and software usage, network, and device connectivity.
- Managed VoIP phone systems, including deploying and supporting phones and extensions.
- Resolved technical problems with Local Area Networks (LAN), phone systems, virtual environments.
- Acted as a point of contact to set up PCs and deploy new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.
- Modify configurations, utilities, software default settings. For the local workstation.
- Build and install new workstations, peripheral equipment, software, and migrate data as part of the upgrade process.

- Ensured each workstation has the necessary equipment needed and any additional specialized equipment to support productivity.
- Maintained an inventory of supplies and spare parts, OEM licensing management.
- Configured and managing user accounts on Active Directory.
- Set up smart conference rooms for meetings, ensuring internet connectivity, and mirroring laptop to the TV for presentations.
- Secured building access controls and observing the uptime of the CCTV system.

DSG Dynamic Solution Group Information Technology Specialist December 2014 - April 2017 (2 years 5 months)

- Cairo Governorate, Egypt
- Developed strong links to internal and external stakeholders.
- Promoted a hardworking, successful, and pleasant team environment.
- Motivated customers to use the company's services more.
- IT-related work involves provisioning and maintaining internal systems, as well as building tools for the automation of routine tasks.
- · Administered mobile device management systems.
- Administered provisioning of new internal hardware and user setup.
- Implemented and maintained an IT asset management system.
- Implemented and monitored security measures for the protection of computer systems, networks, and information.
- Educated users success team on routine problems, to allow them to resolve things directly.
- Assisted users with IT-related issues on-site or remotely.

United Nations OCHA
ICT Associate
March 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 8 months)
Cairo Governorate, Egypt

- Administrated under VMware server (ISA firewall server, Domain server, Data server, WEB servers, FTP server).
- Administrated Lotus Note and Black-Berry service server.
- Administrated the Avaya VOIP server.
- Designed and established a backup strategy for all virtual servers and data.
- Implemented and managed PC setup and deployment for new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.
- Responsible for handling and purchasing IT types of equipment.

- Managed ICT inventory in coordination with the administration unit.
- Provide technical support for specific Satellite internet VSAT, GPS, Thuraya phones.

Vodafone

Account Advisor

June 2009 - March 2012 (2 years 10 months)

Giza Governorate, Egypt

Account advisor-Team leader:

- · Served UK customers in England.
- Set and maintained standards of excellence and professionalism.
- Applied excellent call control to resolve escalated calls successfully.
- Provided customer service support and was their primary escalation point for all customer service.
- Diagnosed and Troubleshoot to solve problems due to Vodafone product issues.
- Log customer complaints and find solutions within determined time frames;
 list suggestions made and analyzed for validity and possible implementation and resolution.
- Reviewed and analyzed historical account information as needed.
- · Corrected transaction mistakes when debits and credits do not balance.
- Resolved problems or discrepancies concerning customers' accounts.
- Assisted with training new hire employees and showing them how to navigate through systems and programs that advisors use daily.
- Developed and coached customer service agents by reviewing recorded calls and providing feedback.
- Assisted customers with questions and concerns that they had regarding why their bill increased, billing cycles, due dates, extensions, etc.

ELNG

IT Support Specialist

2008 - 2009 (1 year)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

Responsible for maintaining and support the following items for entire LNG staff in IDKU site:

 Troubleshoted entire LNG user's software, hardware, and IP phone set conflicts and problems.

- Supported the Windows operating system, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Exchange, Active Directory, PDA interfaces, etc.
- Troubleshoted MFP printers, copiers, digital sender, and faxes problems.
- · Maintained and monitor the network.
- Configured and manage ELNG users' connectivity on Cisco IP telephone.
- Participated in the server's room transfer project.
- Part of the team responsible for implementing the wireless access points plan.

X-Lab Group

IT Support Senior Eng. network administrator August 2006 - February 2008 (1 year 7 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Support Senior Eng. network admin of the Technical Department.

Handling all main project & technical team projects have done:

- The Sharm el-Sheikh International Arbitration Center (shiac.com)
- · network infra cabled and wireless.
- Internet leased line connection with the server firewall.
- lp-sec webcam.
- · Audio and video conference system.
- Smartboard system.
- Kabo JIL factory installing and manager database for 46 fingerprint device.
- IT Support for Lycee Francais Alexandria school (part of the French consul)

 Maintenance contract.

PC LINK

IT Site Maintenance Eng.

January 2005 - August 2006 (1 year 8 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Site Maintenance Eng. for Alexandria Carbon Black Co.

Handling more than 150 PC's, Printers, Copier (hardware & software)

Troubleshooting, maintenance, and networking.

New PC Planet

IT Support

March 1997 - December 2001 (4 years 10 months)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Supervisor in the Technical Support Department.

- · Very good experience in networking.
- Computer assembly.

- Installation of Windows and other common software.
- Troubleshooting most hardware and software problems & hardware conflicts.
- Resolving driver installation problems.
- System admin for the Center for French Studies (CEA) network consisting of 30 PC's and internet leased line.

Education

Special Studies Academy

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering, Quality control and quality assurance for mechanical products. · (1999 - 2003)

College St. Marc, Alexandria

High school degree, Collège Saint Marc · (1983 - 1999)